<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Opinion | Raj Rathore]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/blog/categories/opinion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-26T11:13:28+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raj Rathore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Happened to Indian TV Shows?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/what-happened-to-indian-tv-shows/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T18:28:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/what-happened-to-indian-tv-shows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why can&rsquo;t they create TV shows which have a good script which has good characters and shows high moral values, humane and great and fun to watch and not boring. They do show good guys in these shows but they are all boring, Why a good person has to be boring?</p>

<p>For me there is nothing good on tv, except for IPL. The only Indian TV shows I liked in recent times are &ldquo;Devon ke dev Mahadev&rdquo; &amp; &ldquo;Comedy Nights with Kapil&rdquo;.</p>

<p>If you want my recommendation then please go ahead and watch following tv series, atleast they are interesting, have good script, exciting and will even teach you a lot about life, relationships, friendships, ethics and morality, courage etc&hellip; and they are really fun to watch :&ndash;</p>

<ul>
<li><h4>Friends</h4></li>
<li><h4>The Big Bang Theory</h4></li>
<li><h4>Game of Thrones</h4></li>
<li><h4>Dexter</h4></li>
</ul>


<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Please stop watching these illogical, idiotic shows because they do impact your brain and you&rsquo;ll realize it when you&rsquo;ll finish watching all 10 seasons of Friends and after that you&rsquo;ll hate Indian TV shows&hellip; particulary those which don&rsquo;t have anything decent to show.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Voted for Narendra Modi?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/why-i-voted-for-narendra-modi/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T17:30:17+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/why-i-voted-for-narendra-modi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s election time in India and I did cast my vote on April 17 ( 3 days after my birthday ) and there are plenty who have opinion about Indian youth that &ldquo;Younger generation doesn&rsquo;t understand politics much&rdquo;</p>

<p>I may or may not understand politics much but I think that politicians' speeches and work should be considered as their examination copies.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I draw following conclusions from their speeches:</p>

<p><strong>Rahul Gandhi:</strong> Thinks that people of India are fools or atleast his target audience is less educated. That is why in his speeches he tries to teach people or more appropriately to his party men surrounding him.
I don&rsquo;t know If he knows what he&rsquo;s talking about&hellip; here is Cyrus Broacha&rsquo;s take on Rahul Gandhi&hellip;LOL!!
<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/akCN9yKj3bY "></iframe></div></p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<blockquote><p>Governing a large country
is like frying a small fish.
You spoil it with too much poking. &mdash;Lao Tzu, Tao Te Ching</p></blockquote>

<p>People have come up with statistics in favour or to oppose him, Oxford mathematician Peter Donnelly reveals the common mistakes humans make in interpreting statistics — and the devastating impact these errors can have on the outcome of criminal trials, watch this ted talk.</p>

<iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/lang/en/peter_donnelly_shows_how_stats_fool_juries.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>But people living in Gujarat electing him as CM suggest that he is somewhat more successful than others, he is a good speaker and seems active person, he gave so many speeches and traveled a lot for the campaign&hellip; if he works as PM with this much dedication &amp; positive thinking, he can do a lot.</p>

<blockquote><p>“All that we are is the result of what we have thought. The mind is everything. What we think we become.”- Buddha</p></blockquote>

<p>A positive environment and thinking is necessory for India. So, Narendra Modi became a clear choice&hellip; Now the following question arises</p>

<p><strong>Vote for local candidate or the party/PM candidate?</strong></p>

<p>I think we should vote for Party/PM candidate and not just the candidate unless the candidate is really unworthy/ criminal or corrupt, because:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The Area which comes under the M.P. is too large and even if the candidate says that he will do work and development etc.., He can&rsquo;t do much..yes he can do some work.
I think it&rsquo;s more of the responsibility of the State Government and local authority.</p></li>
<li><p>So the role of M.P. is to know his surrounding, have an idea about needs and problems of the people and give his opinion on the matter. That way he plays some part in policy making and voting on the bills, theoretically. But as we know MPs mostly support their party whether his individual opinion is against the bill.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Thus the real work is done by some ministers and key members of the government/party i.e. Prime Minister &amp; his team.</p>

<p>So I thought, I should vote for good government, good PM based on their stated/ unstated policies.</p>

<p>What did you think before voting and whom did you choose? and if you are going to vote.. who are you going to choose and why?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
