<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Raj Rathore]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-04T13:19:04+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raj Rathore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MyGov: Nice Initiative but Implementation Sucks!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/mygov-nice-initiative-but-implementation-sucks/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-26T16:12:45+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/mygov-nice-initiative-but-implementation-sucks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just had a look at <a href="http://mygov.nic.in" title="MyGov">MyGov</a> website, an initiative by <strong>Narendra Modi﻿</strong>. Website looks nice.. and I was surprised. Because we know how govt websites generally look like.</p>

<p>This website doesn&rsquo;t look like a govt website until you try to use it ;)
And when you try to use it, It&rsquo;s full of flaws and mistakes&hellip; this is a very polite review of the website <strong>MyGov</strong>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You can&rsquo;t signup or sign in. Webpage hangs and slow <strong>server response time</strong>(1.1 seconds), <strong>pageload speed</strong> varies from 5 sec to 60 seconds(<strong>12 seconds</strong> being average). References to the tests are given below this post.</p>

<p>Accidently when you do get successful signup, mail arrives in your spam folder.. Again a hallmark of govt websites and govt professionals. So, You can be sure that you are indeed on a govt. website.</p>

<p>This Idea of listening public opinion is nice but implementation sucks&hellip; that is my first opinion. And I am expressing this opinion on my own blog instead of expressing it on <strong>MyGov</strong> website because I couldn&rsquo;t log in.</p>

<p>It should be easy to signup/login. There is no need to be too much focused on security and doing silly things. Images are good, language used on website is nice and friendly. But Technically it sucks. Make it usable first. I think there are some more serious flaws in the code not just the optimization.</p>

<blockquote><p>“A great lathe operator commands several times the wage of an average lathe operator, but a great writer of software code is worth 10,000 times the price of an average software writer.”
— Bill Gates</p></blockquote>

<p>MyGov dev team needs few such developers who challenge themselves and are exceptionally good. Most govt. professional just do what they must do and not what they should do. Ultimately they end up doing things which they shouldn&rsquo;t do. For example, what is the use of captcha when you can&rsquo;t even implement it well and user can&rsquo;t even signup. Internet connection in India is patchy, they should try to keep the webpage size under few kbs. If this website is intended to be used by public on regular basis then they should&rsquo;ve atleast optimized the website before lauching it.</p>

<p>My advice to developer team of MyGov website: Remove that captcha from signup page. It&rsquo;s very irritating. Also you are asking users to choose a password which has special characters, numbers, capital and small letters&hellip; it&rsquo;s idiotic. It gives a pseudo feeling of security and make people fake believe in security when there is none. Your website is not even using SSL. I&rsquo;m afraid that on this website users&#8217; information is not safe. Optimize your website, improve your code. And try to hire few exceptionally good programmers to do the job and not the army of incompetent programmers.</p>

<p><strong>The website is not even usable forget about security.</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;It is amazing how much can be accomplished if no one cares who gets the credit.&#8221;</p><footer><strong>John Wooden</strong></footer></blockquote>


<p>Thanks!</p>

<h3>References</h3>

<ol>
<li>Page load speed and analysis of MyGov.nic.in by <a href="http://gtmetrix.com/reports/mygov.nic.in/QXlKHu3b">gtmetrix</a></li>
<li>Page Load speed and analysis of MyGov.nic.in by <a href="http://tools.pingdom.com/fpt/#!/bqA8wx/mygov.nic.in">Pingdom</a></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncertain Observer]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/uncertain-observer/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-08T12:04:54+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/uncertain-observer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Heisenberg</strong> and <strong>Schrödinger</strong> get pulled over for speeding. <br/>
The cop asks Heisenberg &ldquo;Do you know how fast you were going?&#8221;<br/>
Heisenberg replies, &#8220;No, but we know exactly where we are!&#8221;<br/>
The officer looks at him confused and says &#8220;you were going 108 miles per hour!&#8221;<br/>
Heisenberg throws his arms up and cries, &#8220;Great! Now we&rsquo;re lost!&#8221;<br/>
The officer looks over the car and asks Schrödinger if the two men have anything in the trunk.<br/>
&#8220;A cat,&rdquo; Schrödinger replies. <br/>
The cop opens the trunk and yells &ldquo;Hey! This cat is dead.&#8221;<br/>
Schrödinger angrily replies, &#8220;Well he is now.&rdquo;</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p>[Explaination: <strong>Schrödinger&rsquo;s</strong> cat is a thought experiment, sometimes described as a paradox, devised by Austrian physicist Erwin Schrödinger in 1935. It illustrates what he saw as the problem of the Copenhagen interpretation of quantum mechanics applied to everyday objects. The scenario presents a cat that may be both alive and dead, this state being tied to an earlier random event. Although the original &ldquo;experiment&rdquo; was imaginary, similar principles have been researched and used in practical applications. The thought experiment is also often featured in theoretical discussions of the interpretations of quantum mechanics. In the course of developing this experiment, Schrödinger coined the term Verschränkung (entanglement).</p>

<p>In quantum mechanics, the <strong>uncertainty principle</strong> is any of a variety of mathematical inequalities asserting a fundamental limit to the precision with which certain pairs of physical properties of a particle known as complementary variables
]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renew Heroku SSL Certificate by Godaddy]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/renew-heroku-ssl-certificate-issued-by-godaddy/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-05T09:16:32+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/renew-heroku-ssl-certificate-issued-by-godaddy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently renewed my ssl cert for heroku hosted domain registered at godaddy. This post is a how to Guide for renewing/updating SSL Certificate issued by godaddy for heroku hosted domain without changing dns and keeping old ssl endpoint url. I hope it&rsquo;ll help somebody.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Step 1: Renew Godaddy certificate</h3>

<p>Apply renewal credit at godaddy and use the previous certificate signing request(csr), selecting option of third party hosted domain and submit.</p>

<h3>Step 2: Download Certificates Zip and Combine Certs</h3>

<p>After the certificate has been issued by godaddy, download certs for &lsquo;Nginx&rsquo; server. unzip the zipped file, cd into directory, and combine certificates.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">cat</span> <span class="mi">48</span><span class="n">bcdx31xxxx</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">crt</span> <span class="n">sf_bundle</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">g2</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">g1</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">crt</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="n">combined</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">crt</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Step 3: Update Certificate at Heroku SSL Endpoint</h3>

<p>run certificate update command</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">heroku</span> <span class="ss">certs</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="n">update</span> <span class="n">combined</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">crt</span> <span class="n">server</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">key</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Confirm the changes by typing app_name.</p>

<h3>Step 4: Check Certificate Info</h3>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="n">heroku</span> <span class="ss">certs</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="n">info</span> <span class="o">--</span><span class="n">app</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">app_name</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Step 5: Done!</h3>

<p>Done! and after few seconds app is running on previous ssl endpoint url. So, No need to update dns.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Note on the Perks of Being a Wallflower]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/a-note-on-perks-of-being-a-wallflower/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-07T20:47:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/a-note-on-perks-of-being-a-wallflower</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spend a lot of time on computer and not so much with books. I do read blogs, articles and even documentations of software but not novels. But this week I read <strong>&ldquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower&rdquo;</strong>. The last novel which I read was <strong>The Alchemist</strong>. Written by <strong>Stephen Chbosky</strong>, <strong>&ldquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower&rdquo;</strong> is really a fantastic book.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.rajrathore.com/images/posts/the-perks-of-being-a-wallflower.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="The Perks of being a Wallflower Cover" alt="The Perks of being a Wallflower Cover"></p>

<p>I think I can relate to charlie somewhere. I think a lot many can relate to him. The small little nitty gritty details about people which you notice and don&rsquo;t write, is written in this book. Most people are too obsessed with themselves and their life that they ignore what&rsquo;s happening around them.</p>

<p>Charlie is this kid who knows what&rsquo;s happening around him and he keeps quite about them, he introspects and he understands. He&rsquo;s a Wallflower.</p>

<p>Charlie is not the biggest geek in the school, he is by no means popular. Shy, introspective, intelligent beyond his years yet socially awkward, caught between trying to live his life and trying to run from it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I learned a lot from this book, but most importantly I learned that it&rsquo;s okay to feel things and be who you are about them.</p>

<p>I also learned few new english words. Nice addition to my English vocab. I&rsquo;m an Indian guy so my english is not that good. These words are valedictorian, silhouette, vented, primping, bleachers, corny and sorority.</p>

<p>Language is fluent. Small and large letters with all details. Letters always establish some sort of bond. They feel personal and touch reader&rsquo;s heart.</p>

<p>I probably quote the whole book but still I&rsquo;m mentioning some quotes below.</p>

<h3>Few Quotes from &ldquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower&rdquo; which I admire:&ndash;</h3>

<blockquote><p>I just think it&#8217;s bad when a boy looks at a girl and thinks that the way he sees the girl is better than the girl actually is. And I think it&#8217;s bad when the most honest way a boy can look at a girl is through a camera. It&#8217;s very hard for me to see Sam feel better about herself just because an older boy sees her that way.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<p></p>

<blockquote><p>I just hope I remember to tell my kids that they are as happy as I look in my old photographs.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<p></p>

<blockquote><p>So, this is my life. And I want you to know that I am both happy and sad and I&#8217;m still trying to figure out how that could be.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>Things change. And friends leave. Life doesn&#8217;t stop for anybody.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>Charlie, We accept the love we think we deserve.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>I think that if I ever have kids, and they are upset, I won&#8217;t tell them that people are starving in China or anything like that because it wouldn&#8217;t change the fact that they were upset. And even if somebody else has it much worse, that doesn&#8217;t really change the fact that you have what you have.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>Sometimes people use thought to not participate in life.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>Be skeptical ablout this one. It&#8217;s a great book. But try to be a filter, not a sponge.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>“We didn&#8217;t talk about anything heavy or light. We were just there together. And that was enough”</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>And I guess I realized at that moment that I really did love her. Because there was nothing to gain, and that didn&#8217;t matter.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>I just want you to know that you’re very special… and the only reason I&#8217;m telling you is that I don’t know if anyone else ever has.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>If somebody likes me, I want them to like the real me, not what they think I am. And I don&#8217;t want them to carry it around inside. I want them to show me, so I can feel it, too. I want them to be able to do whatever they want around me.</p><footer><strong>Sam</strong></footer></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>Maybe it&#8217;s good to put things in perspective, but sometimes, I think that the only perspective is to really be there. Like Sam Said. Because it&#8217;s okay to feel things. And be who you are about them.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>


<h3>Charlie&rsquo;s mixtape</h3>

<blockquote><p>-    Asleep by the Smiths<br/>-  Vapour Trail by Ride<br/>-  Scarborough Fair by Simon & Garfunkel<br/>- A Whiter Shade of Pale by Procol Harum<br/>-    Dear Prudence by the Beatles<br/>-  Gypsy by Suzanne Vega<br/>- Nights in White Satin by the Moody Blues<br/>-  Daydream by Smashing Pumpkins<br/>- Dusk by Genesis (before Phil Collins was even in the band!)<br/>-   MLK by U2<br/>- Blackbird by the Beatles<br/>-  Landslide by Fleetwood Mac<br/>-    Asleep by the Smiths (again!)</p><footer><strong>Charlie&#8217;s mixtape</strong></footer></blockquote>


<p>Going to download these songs and listen. I think I&rsquo;ll read this book again sometime or whenever I want to feel good about things or understand things a little better.</p>

<p>Also It&rsquo;s the first book which I read on my iPad. iBooks is a nice app for reading. Highlighting, taking notes and bookmarks, checking definitions of words&hellip; it&rsquo;s really great. Good start!</p>

<p>And The next book which I&rsquo;m going to read is by <strong>Jean-Paul Sartre, Nausea</strong>. It&rsquo;s a gift from a friend. I hopefully start reading it this week.</p>

<p>Well done, <strong>Stephen Chbosky</strong>. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bought Hitachi Ace Reidan Hot &amp; Cold AC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/bought-hitachi-reidan-ahot-and-cold-ac/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T17:45:41+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/bought-hitachi-reidan-ahot-and-cold-ac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday we bought a new air conditioner and it&rsquo;s a Hitachi Ace Reidan 1.5 Ton Split AC. We bought this model because it&rsquo;s a hot &amp; cold air conditioner and we already have a Hitachi Ace Cutout which performs well.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.rajrathore.com/images/posts/hitachi_ace_reidan.jpg" width="600" height="250" title="Hitachi Ace Reidan" alt="Hitachi Ace Reidan"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Buying another AC from the same company has its advantages, the remote of Ace Reidan also works with Ace cutout. That&rsquo;s a nice thing. And If a service guy come to check one AC, he can check the other AC as well, saves a trip for the service guy.</p>

<p>There is not much difference between the price of these two air conditioners and not much difference in features as well. Hitachi Ace Reidan is a hot and cold air conditioner and will work in winters while Ace cutout takes a sleep in winter. The difference is Ace reidan reverses the cycle and provide hot air when switched to hot mode.</p>

<p>The difference in favor of ace cutout is that it has a energy star rating of 5 while Ace Reidan is still unrated probably because it&rsquo;s a new model.</p>

<p>But It seems like there is not much difference between the two ACs.
Ace Reidan with stabilizer, installation and a bit of electricity fitting, cost us around 48,500/&ndash; INR. Ace cutout costs a few thousand less.</p>

<p>Winter is coming!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Localhost Tunneling, Working With Facebook Open Graph]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/localhost-tunneling-working-with-facebook-open-graph/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-26T09:39:18+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/localhost-tunneling-working-with-facebook-open-graph</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m currently developing an app which uses facebook Open graph API. Using localhost works fine with facebook authentication but when you want to use graph api then facebook needs access to the webpage, so that it can parse open graph meta tags.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The solution to this problem is either deploy your app online or allow localhost tunneling so that facebook can access it. I prefer localhost tunneling when working in my development environment.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='ngrok securely exposes a local web server to the internet and capture all traffic for detailed inspection and replay'>
I use <a href="https://ngrok.com/"><strong>ngrok</strong></a>. ngrok securely exposes a local web server to the internet and capture all traffic for detailed inspection and replay and it worked well with facebook.
</span>
<strong>ngrok</strong> is easy to use and it takes just 2 minutes to signup and expose your webserver. Sign up is not required but it doesn&rsquo;t take much time so I did.</p>

<h2>Steps</h2>

<h3>1. Download ngrok</h3>

<p>I downloaded ngrok on my mac but it&rsquo;s available for windows and linux as well. it&rsquo;s just a small zip file, just takes few seconds to download.</p>

<h3>2. unzip it</h3>

<pre><code>unzip /path/to/ngrok.zip
</code></pre>

<h3>3. Run it</h3>

<pre><code>ngrok -authtoken your_auth_token port
</code></pre>

<p>in above command <strong>your_auth_token</strong> is your authentication token and <strong>port</strong> is the port which you want to expose.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>ngrok</span><a href='https://ngrok.com/'>link </a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="no">Tunnel</span> <span class="no">Status</span>                 <span class="n">online</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Version</span>                       <span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">6</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">5</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Forwarding</span>                    <span class="ss">http</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="sr">//</span><span class="mi">9</span><span class="n">d322c2</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">ngrok</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">com</span> <span class="o">-&gt;</span> <span class="mi">127</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="mi">80</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Forwarding</span>                    <span class="ss">https</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="sr">//</span><span class="mi">9</span><span class="n">d322c2</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">ngrok</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">com</span> <span class="o">-&gt;</span> <span class="mi">127</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="mi">80</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Web</span> <span class="no">Interface</span>                 <span class="mi">127</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="mi">4040</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="c1"># Conn                        0</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="no">Avg</span> <span class="no">Conn</span> <span class="no">Time</span>                 <span class="mi">0</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span><span class="n">ms</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>where <a href="http://9d322c2.ngrok.com">http://9d322c2.ngrok.com</a> is the url which you can use to access your local web server. I have closed this tunnel, So you won&rsquo;t able to access this url, it&rsquo;s just for example purpose here.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Happened to Indian TV Shows?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/what-happened-to-indian-tv-shows/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T18:28:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/what-happened-to-indian-tv-shows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was switching TV channels and happened to be on ZeeTV accidently.
This show was showing some guy burning restaurent of a girl to take revenge of an insult&hellip; another similar type of show is <strong>Madhubala</strong> which is  on Colors. The common thing which is happening in these shows or their  storyline is a guy treats girl like dirt and then they show that he is actually a nice person&hellip; and then she fall for him.
I find these shows absurd.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why can&rsquo;t they create TV shows which have a good scripts with good characters and high moral values, humane and fun to watch and not boring. They do show good guys in these shows but they are all boring, Why a good person has to be boring? It&rsquo;s just a pure prejudice. A person has many facet to his personality, for example &ldquo;amazing spider man&rdquo;, he is cool, interesting and does what is right, is a good hero.</p>

<p>For me there is nothing good on tv, except for IPL. The only Indian TV shows I liked in recent times are &ldquo;Devon ke dev Mahadev&rdquo; &amp; &ldquo;Comedy Nights with Kapil&rdquo;.</p>

<p>If you want my recommendation then please go ahead and watch following tv series, atleast they are interesting, have good script, exciting and if you try to be a filter and not a sponge then these shows will even teach you a lot about life, relationships, friendships, ethics and morality, courage etc&hellip; and they are really fun to watch :&ndash;</p>

<ul>
<li><h4>Friends</h4></li>
<li><h4>The Big Bang Theory</h4></li>
<li><h4>Game of Thrones</h4></li>
<li><h4>Dexter</h4></li>
</ul>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Even Disney doesn&#8217;t have any good shows for kids&#8230; I still remember shows like Duck tales, Talespin etc.'>
Sometimes I think
&ldquo;Aadhi Indian public ka dimag toh in tv shows ne kharab kar diya h&hellip;&rdquo;
and I  think Indian TV shows&#8217; quality is really deteriorating&hellip;  Even Disney doesn&rsquo;t have any good shows for kids&hellip; I still remember shows like Duck tales, Talespin etc. but now they are using too much effects and all.. but no good story. I think Disney should rerun old shows instead of these crappy shows which they are making for kids. Pogo has a nice show called &ldquo;Chota Bheem&rdquo; and they telecast this show all day, So not much for kids on TV also.
</span></p>

<p>Please stop watching these illogical, idiotic shows because they do impact your brain and you&rsquo;ll realize it when you&rsquo;ll finish watching all 10 seasons of Friends and after that you&rsquo;ll hate Indian TV shows&hellip; particulary those which don&rsquo;t have anything decent to show.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Got This Domain?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/how-i-got-this-domain/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-23T15:26:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/how-i-got-this-domain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I needed to make a matrimonial bio-data and I thought it would be convenient for me as well as for them to view my bio-data online instead of opening email everytime to view my bio-data&hellip; So, I thought of setting up a small website and provide the url to them&hellip; also It allows me to make changes to it if asked for more information&hellip;</p>

<p>I did a look up on Godaddy and&hellip; <strong>Voila!!</strong> <strong>rajrathore.com</strong> and <strong>rajrathore.me</strong> was available. <strong>Raj</strong> is a pretty common name in India and there are lots of <strong>Rathores</strong>&hellip; but I guess very few are programmers.. that increased my chances of getting this domain.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='A domain name with your own name is a really good thing to possess.'>
A domain name with your own name is a really good thing to possess.
</span></p>

<p>I registered the domain and took a template and filled it up with all the details and uploaded to the server, just in two hours&hellip; editing template &amp; adding information took some time, everything else was snappy.</p>

<p>I never needed a bio-data, so I never set it up&hellip; and I think, I&rsquo;m never going to need one except for this one scenario&hellip;
.. I&rsquo;ll make a nice well-designed/well-crafted profile someday&hellip;</p>

<p>Bio-data is just summary of a person and I think a person&rsquo;s writing style also tells a lot about a person as well&hellip;</p>

<p>Read my blogs and know my thinking, <br/>
See my work and know my skills,<br/>
Spend time with me and know me as a human being&hellip;<br/>
Task simplified!!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m considering of writing more often and as it happens with other skills, more time you invest, better you become!</p>

<p>Have a nice day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
    
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Voted for Narendra Modi?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/why-i-voted-for-narendra-modi/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-22T17:30:17+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/why-i-voted-for-narendra-modi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s election time in India and I did cast my vote on April 17 ( 3 days after my birthday ) and there are plenty who have opinion about Indian youth that &ldquo;Younger generation doesn&rsquo;t understand politics much&rdquo;</p>

<p>I may or may not understand politics much but I think that politicians&#8217; speeches and work should be considered as their examination copies.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I draw following conclusions from their speeches:</p>

<p><strong>Rahul Gandhi:</strong> Thinks that people of India are fools or atleast his target audience is less educated. That is why in his speeches he tries to teach people or more appropriately to his party men surrounding him.
I don&rsquo;t know If he knows what he&rsquo;s talking about&hellip; here is Cyrus Broacha&rsquo;s take on Rahul Gandhi&hellip;LOL!!</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/akCN9yKj3bY "></iframe></div>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='In trying to prove himself right, he proved those wrong who trusted him and voted for him'>
<strong>Arvind Kejriwal:</strong> Thinks that people of India are &ldquo;Bechari Janta&rdquo; or &ldquo;AAM or chusa hua AAM admi&rdquo;. He resigned from a great opportunity which was given to him. In trying to prove himself right, he proved those wrong who trusted him and voted for him and then he resigned on a issue. I don&rsquo;t want to tell my opinion about every idea he has in mind, everytime&hellip; that&rsquo;s his referendum bullshit&hellip; I have other things to do&hellip;  We choose/trust government to do work for us&hellip;
</span></p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='If India has to grow, India needs something similar to Silicon Valley'>
<strong>Narendra Modi:</strong> Thinks that people of india have potential to make India shine on world canvas. He thinks that people of india are smart, intelligent and not bechara. If given a chance people can achieve incredible things. He favours entreprenuership and business&hellip; If India has to grow, India needs something similar to Silicon Valley..
So far India is obsessed with jobs and govt. job psychology to the extreme level&hellip; His idea of minimum government, maximum governence is also really awesome approach..
</span></p>

<blockquote><p>Governing a large country
is like frying a small fish.
You spoil it with too much poking. &mdash;Lao Tzu, Tao Te Ching</p></blockquote>

<p>People have come up with statistics in favour or to oppose him, Oxford mathematician Peter Donnelly reveals the common mistakes humans make in interpreting statistics — and the devastating impact these errors can have on the outcome of criminal trials, watch this ted talk.</p>

<iframe src="http://embed.ted.com/talks/lang/en/peter_donnelly_shows_how_stats_fool_juries.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>But people living in Gujarat electing him as CM suggest that he is somewhat more successful than others, he is a good speaker and seems active person, he gave so many speeches and traveled a lot for the campaign&hellip; if he works as PM with this much dedication &amp; positive thinking, he can do a lot.</p>

<blockquote><p>“All that we are is the result of what we have thought. The mind is everything. What we think we become.”- Buddha</p></blockquote>

<p>A positive environment and thinking is necessory for India. So, Narendra Modi became a clear choice&hellip; Now the following question arises</p>

<p><strong>Vote for local candidate or the party/PM candidate?</strong></p>

<p>I think we should vote for Party/PM candidate and not just the candidate unless the candidate is really unworthy/ criminal or corrupt, because:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The Area which comes under the M.P. is too large and even if the candidate says that he will do work and development etc.., He can&rsquo;t do much..yes he can do some work.
I think it&rsquo;s more of the responsibility of the State Government and local authority.</p></li>
<li><p>So the role of M.P. is to know his surrounding, have an idea about needs and problems of the people and give his opinion on the matter. That way he plays some part in policy making and voting on the bills, theoretically. But as we know MPs mostly support their party whether his individual opinion is against the bill.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Thus the real work is done by some ministers and key members of the government/party i.e. Prime Minister &amp; his team.</p>

<p>So I thought, I should vote for good government, good PM based on their stated/ unstated policies.</p>

<p>What did you think before voting and whom did you choose? and if you are going to vote.. who are you going to choose and why?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
    
  
</feed>
