<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | Raj Rathore]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-23T18:49:38+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raj Rathore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Did I Get This Domain?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/how-did-i-get-this-domain/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-23T15:26:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/how-did-i-get-this-domain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I needed to make a resume or biodata to give it to someone for the post of becoming a husband..:) yeah, it was a matrimonial biodata and I thought it would be convenient for me as well as for them to view my biodata online instead of opening email everytime to view the biodata&hellip; So, I thought of setting up a small website and provide the url to them&hellip; also It allows me to make changes to it if asked for more information&hellip;</p>

<p>I did a look up on Godaddy and&hellip; <strong>Voila!!</strong> <strong>rajrathore.com</strong> and <strong>rajrathore.me</strong> is available. I didn&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ll get this domain. Raj is a pretty common name in India and there are lots of Rathores&hellip; but I guess very few are programmers.. that helped.
A domain name with your own name is a really good thing to possess.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I registered the domain and took a template and filled it up with all the details and uploaded to the server, just in two hours&hellip; adding information took time, everything else was snappy.</p>

<p>I never needed a biodata, so I never set it up&hellip; and I think, I&rsquo;m never going to need one except for this one scenario&hellip;
.. I&rsquo;ll make a nice well-designed/well-crafted profile someday&hellip;</p>

<p>Biodata is just summary of a person and I think, A person&rsquo;s writing style also tells a lot about a person as well&hellip;</p>

<p>Read my blogs and know my thinking, <br/>
See my work and know my skills,<br/>
Spend time with me and know me as a human being&hellip;<br/>
Task simplified!!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m thinking of writing more often and as it happens with other skills, more time you invest, better you become!</p>

<p>Have a nice day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
