<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | Raj Rathore]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-08T12:18:06+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raj Rathore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Note on the Perks of Being a Wallflower]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/a-note-on-perks-of-being-a-wallflower/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-07T20:47:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/a-note-on-perks-of-being-a-wallflower</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spend a lot of time on computer and not so much with books. I do read blogs, articles and even documentations of software but not novels. But this week I read <strong>&ldquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower&rdquo;</strong>. The last novel which I read was <strong>The Alchemist</strong>. Written by <strong>Stephen Chbosky</strong>, <strong>&ldquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower&rdquo;</strong> is really a fantastic book.</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/the-perks-of-being-a-wallflower.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="&lsquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower Cover&rsquo; &lsquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower Cover&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>I think I can relate to charlie somewhere. I think a lot many can relate to him. The small little nitty gritty details about people which you notice and don&rsquo;t write, is written in this book. Most people are too obsessed with themselves and their life that they ignore what&rsquo;s happening around them.</p>

<p>Charlie is this kid who knows what&rsquo;s happening around him and he keeps quite about them, he introspects and he understands. He&rsquo;s a Wallflower.</p>

<p>Charlie is not the biggest geek in the school, he is by no means popular. Shy, introspective, intelligent beyond his years yet socially awkward, caught between trying to live his life and trying to run from it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I learned a lot from this book, but most importantly I learned that it&rsquo;s okay to feel things and be who you are about them.</p>

<p>I also learned few new english words. Nice addition to my English vocab. I&rsquo;m an Indian guy so my english is not that good. These words are valedictorian, silhouette, vented, primping, bleachers, corny and sorority.</p>

<p>Language is fluent. Small and large letters with all details. Letters always establish some sort of bond. They feel personal and touch reader&rsquo;s heart.</p>

<p>I probably quote the whole book but still I&rsquo;m mentioning some quotes below.</p>

<h3>Few Quotes from &ldquo;The Perks of being a Wallflower&rdquo; which I admire:&ndash;</h3>

<p><blockquote><p>I just think it&rsquo;s bad when a boy looks at a girl and thinks that the way he sees the girl is better than the girl actually is. And I think it&rsquo;s bad when the most honest way a boy can look at a girl is through a camera. It&rsquo;s very hard for me to see Sam feel better about herself just because an older boy sees her that way.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote><br/>
<blockquote><p>I just hope I remember to tell my kids that they are as happy as I look in my old photographs.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote> <br/>
<blockquote><p>So, this is my life. And I want you to know that I am both happy and sad and I&rsquo;m still trying to figure out how that could be.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Things change. And friends leave. Life doesn&rsquo;t stop for anybody.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Charlie, We accept the love we think we deserve.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>I think that if I ever have kids, and they are upset, I won&rsquo;t tell them that people are starving in China or anything like that because it wouldn&rsquo;t change the fact that they were upset. And even if somebody else has it much worse, that doesn&rsquo;t really change the fact that you have what you have.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Sometimes people use thought to not participate in life.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Be skeptical ablout this one. It&rsquo;s a great book. But try to be a filter, not a sponge.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>“We didn&rsquo;t talk about anything heavy or light. We were just there together. And that was enough”</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>And I guess I realized at that moment that I really did love her. Because there was nothing to gain, and that didn&rsquo;t matter.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>I just want you to know that you’re very special… and the only reason I&rsquo;m telling you is that I don’t know if anyone else ever has.</p><footer><strong>Bill</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>If somebody likes me, I want them to like the real me, not what they think I am. And I don&rsquo;t want them to carry it around inside. I want them to show me, so I can feel it, too. I want them to be able to do whatever they want around me.</p><footer><strong>Sam</strong></footer></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Maybe it&rsquo;s good to put things in perspective, but sometimes, I think that the only perspective is to really be there. Like Sam Said. Because it&rsquo;s okay to feel things. And be who you are about them.</p><footer><strong>Charlie</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<h3>Charlie&rsquo;s mixtape</h3>

<p><blockquote><p>&ndash;   Asleep by the Smiths<br/>&ndash;   Vapour Trail by Ride<br/>&ndash;   Scarborough Fair by Simon &amp; Garfunkel<br/>&ndash;   A Whiter Shade of Pale by Procol Harum<br/>&ndash;   Dear Prudence by the Beatles<br/>&ndash;   Gypsy by Suzanne Vega<br/>&ndash;   Nights in White Satin by the Moody Blues<br/>&ndash;   Daydream by Smashing Pumpkins<br/>&ndash;   Dusk by Genesis (before Phil Collins was even in the band!)<br/>&ndash;   MLK by U2<br/>&ndash;   Blackbird by the Beatles<br/>&ndash;   Landslide by Fleetwood Mac<br/>&ndash;   Asleep by the Smiths (again!)</p><footer><strong>Charlie&rsquo;s mixtape</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>Going to download these songs and listen. I think I&rsquo;ll read this book again sometime or whenever I want to feel good about things or understand things a little better.</p>

<p>Also It&rsquo;s the first book which I read on my iPad. iBooks is a nice app for reading. Highlighting, taking notes and bookmarks, checking definitions of words&hellip; it&rsquo;s really great. Good start!</p>

<p>And The next book which I&rsquo;m going to read is by <strong>Jean-Paul Sartre, Nausea</strong>. It&rsquo;s a gift from a friend. I hopefully start reading it this week.</p>

<p>Well done, <strong>Stephen Chbosky</strong>. Thanks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
