<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Products | Raj Rathore]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/blog/categories/products/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-16T23:20:50+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Raj Rathore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bought Hitachi Ace Reidan Hot &amp; Cold AC]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rajrathore.com/bought-hitachi-reidan-ahot-and-cold-ac/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T17:45:41+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://www.rajrathore.com/bought-hitachi-reidan-ahot-and-cold-ac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday we bought a new air conditioner and it&rsquo;s a Hitachi Ace Reidan 1.5 Ton Split AC. We bought this model because it&rsquo;s a hot &amp; cold air conditioner and we already have a Hitachi Ace Cutout which performs well.</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/hitachi_ace_reidan.jpg" width="600" height="250" title="&lsquo;Hitachi Ace Reidan&rsquo; &lsquo;Hitachi Ace Reidan&rsquo;" ></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Buying another AC from the same company has its advantages, the remote of Ace Reidan also works with Ace cutout. That&rsquo;s a nice thing. And If a service guy come to check one AC, he can check the other AC as well, saves a trip for the service guy.</p>

<p>There is not much difference between the price of these two air conditioners and not much difference in features as well. Hitachi Ace Reidan is a hot and cold air conditioner and will work in winters while Ace cutout takes a sleep in winter. The difference is Ace reidan reverses the cycle and provide hot air when switched to hot mode.</p>

<p>The difference in favor of ace cutout is that it has a energy star rating of 5 while Ace Reidan is still unrated probably because it&rsquo;s a new model.</p>

<p>But It seems like there is not much difference between the two ACs.
Ace Reidan with stabilizer, installation and a bit of electricity fitting, cost us around 48,500/&ndash; INR. Ace cutout costs a few thousand less.</p>

<p>Winter is coming!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
